<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2019 on Sayan Bhowmik</title>
    <link>https://snbk97.github.io/tags/2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2019 on Sayan Bhowmik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019 Sayan Bhowmik</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 22:25:40 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://snbk97.github.io/tags/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Review</title>
      <link>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/2019-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 22:25:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/2019-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;2019&lt;/code&gt; - The year of Keanu Reves memes, Tesla&#39;s cyber truck, Greta Thunberg&#39;s concern for the environment, ISRO&#39;s Chandrayaan-2 success et cetera&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, It was a pretty good year for me as well. It was one of the year which had overwhelmed me with what it had to offer in both ways - positive and negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt some very ancient but also few interesting tech in college like 6Bone, MobileIP, Computer graphics, Turing machines (almost flunked), last but not least, exciting tech : Java servlet 2.0 (/s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I completed my 4th and 5th semesters in college, which is pretty great news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some how managed to get a software engineering internship and hope to  get the full-time position also. The preparation for which somewhat a mixture of hard work and LOT OF LUCK. To be honest, it was fucking annoying at best, to go through at least 3-4 interviews (till the last round), just to hear the same sh*t &amp;ldquo;Better Luck Next Time. Kek&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JK, it was more like - Good luck for your next interviews, f*ck off now m8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New habit, that I&#39;m of looking into - Listening to podcasts and talk shows. People really talk about really fascinating things about life, thoughts, food, religion and most importantly TECH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To name a few -&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Podcast&lt;/strong&gt; - Lex Fridman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If then else&lt;/strong&gt; - Mayuko&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashdin Doctor&lt;/strong&gt; - Habit coach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Vinamre Kasanaa show&lt;/strong&gt; - Vinamre Kasana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PG Radio&lt;/strong&gt; - Prakhar Gupta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to the end of this post, I&#39;m left with 6 more months of college, which will be spent mostly in the internship and hopefully other productive things.
Let&#39;s see what 2020 brings us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~fin&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
