<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sayan Bhowmik</title>
    <link>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sayan Bhowmik</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2019 Sayan Bhowmik</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 22:25:40 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://snbk97.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Review</title>
      <link>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/2019-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 22:25:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/2019-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;2019&lt;/code&gt; - The year of Keanu Reves memes, Tesla&#39;s cyber truck, Greta Thunberg&#39;s concern for the environment, ISRO&#39;s Chandrayaan-2 success et cetera&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, It was a pretty good year for me as well. It was one of the year which had overwhelmed me with what it had to offer in both ways - positive and negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt some very ancient but also few interesting tech in college like 6Bone, MobileIP, Computer graphics, Turing machines (almost flunked), last but not least, exciting tech : Java servlet 2.0 (/s)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I completed my 4th and 5th semesters in college, which is pretty great news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some how managed to get a software engineering internship and hope to  get the full-time position also. The preparation for which somewhat a mixture of hard work and LOT OF LUCK. To be honest, it was fucking annoying at best, to go through at least 3-4 interviews (till the last round), just to hear the same sh*t &amp;ldquo;Better Luck Next Time. Kek&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JK, it was more like - Good luck for your next interviews, f*ck off now m8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New habit, that I&#39;m looking into - listening to podcasts and talk shows. People really talk about really fascinating things about life, thoughts, food, religion and most importantly TECH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To name a few -&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Podcast&lt;/strong&gt; - Lex Fridman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If then else&lt;/strong&gt; - Mayuko&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit Coach&lt;/strong&gt; - Ashdin Doctor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Vinamre Kasanaa show&lt;/strong&gt; - Vinamre Kasana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PG Radio&lt;/strong&gt; - Prakhar Gupta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to the end of this post, I&#39;m left with 6 more months of college, which will be spent mostly in the internship and hopefully other productive things.
Let&#39;s see what 2020 brings us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~fin&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Mental Models - 3</title>
      <link>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/tgmm-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 01:03:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/tgmm-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are around 9 mental models mentioned in the The Great Mental Models book. I&#39;m going to
describe last but not the least resonating mental model of them, which is know
as &lt;code&gt;Occam&#39;s Razor&lt;/code&gt;. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/2017/05/mental-model-occams-razor/&#34;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occam&#39;s Razor is a principle, which state that - &lt;code&gt;Suppose there exist two explanations for an occurrence. In this case the one that requires the least speculation is usually correct. Another way of saying it is that the more assumptions you have to make, the more unlikely an explanation.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://simple.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occam%27s_razor&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In layman&#39;s word, it simply means - If there is a simple way to prove
a hypothesis, then there is no need to bring in superfluous/complex elements
into the discussion, which can lead to difficulty to test and prove the
hypothesis itself. The simplest explanations are more likely to be correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Said that, simplicity doesn&#39;t mean brevity. Explaining brief of the problem, or
approaching part of a solution is not what we want. Occam&#39;s Razor principle is
used to eliminate anything surplus, which is unnecessary in explaining or
proving the hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an example from Wikipedia page.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Two trees have fallen down during a windy night. Think about these two possible
explanations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wind has blown them down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two meteorites have each taken one tree down and, after striking the trees, hit each other removing any trace of themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a quote by Einstein to sum it up: &lt;code&gt;Everything should be made as simple as possible, but not simpler.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Mental Models - 2</title>
      <link>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/tgmm-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 21:36:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/tgmm-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuing with the previous [&lt;a href=&#34;../tgmm-1&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;], I want to talk about the next
mental model that is know as &lt;code&gt;Second-order thinking&lt;/code&gt;[&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/2016/04/second-order-thinking/&#34;&gt;Read
More&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mental model enables us to evaluate our decision that we take to solve our
problems for the time being and not worry about it&#39;s consequence in the
long run. It&#39;s fast, easy and instant. No need to scratch you head to think
about the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, Second Order thinking need a little time to think and consider
the consequence which you might face in the long term because of this one
decision you make. Sometime it&#39;s not enough to think to the second order, we
can choose to think even one step further to the Third Order of thinking.
The decisions we make must have an answer to &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; we are taking this decision
in every step of the way. Is it valuable in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A excellent example given in the book was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding more traction to car tires, makes it easier to control on the roads and
slides less. (This is an example of first order thinking)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the second order thinking comes into play if we think about the effects
it&#39;s going to have on the environment and the car parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to more traction, the engine now has to work harder, resulting in less
mileage of the vehicle. Also this cause more emission in the
environment and more rubber particles left out in the ground. (Second order
thinking)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Mental Models - 1</title>
      <link>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/tgmm-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 20:12:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/tgmm-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my review of the book &amp;ldquo;The Great Mental Models&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog&#34;&gt;Shane
Parrish&lt;/a&gt;. In
this review, I will talk about the things that rather resonated with my
thinking. The main focus of mental models is to look at problems in a more
holistic way and then approach their solution. This was covered in the &lt;code&gt;Thought Experiment&lt;/code&gt; chapter of this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must be wondering what mental models actually are. Okay, so let me tell you
what I understood from it. Mental models are a way of seeing the world from
many different angles and comprehend how the world works.
So when you are thinking of solutions, think in every angle possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;It is advised to learn multiple mental model and apply them in your life, so that you don&#39;t have to distort reality to fit your mental models.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we think about solving a problem, we most often think about the solution
in the same domain in which the problem lies. This is where we must try to
understand the gravity of the problem in multiple disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a researcher, you think in term of success rates of experiments and
reports. Similarly, if you&#39;re a business man, you think in term of profit or
loss of your company&#39;s revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how the process of thinking is embedded into out brain via the
education system and work environments. This not a bad way of thinking, it does
comes handy to prevent common mistakes. But, it does &lt;strong&gt;narrow&lt;/strong&gt; our vision towards
the issue and how we perceive the world and problems associated in within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to know more, visit the author&#39;s blog post.[&lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/2017/06/thought-experiment-how-einstein-solved-difficult-problems/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The `ls` Guide</title>
      <link>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/using-ls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 23:42:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/using-ls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You must be wondering why even bother reading a post about &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; command out of all the commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s hard to remember all the options, so here&#39;s a cheat sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s a handy tool to search through a pile of files, so why not read more about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some awesome tools, I came across - &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;shared at the end&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; -&lt;/strong&gt; this command is used for listing directory contents on *nix OS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SYNTAX -&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;ls [OPTION] [FILE]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Popular Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; - lists contents with almost no formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls -l&lt;/code&gt; - formatted as a list; shows more info shown such as: permissions, date, time, author, owner etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls -a&lt;/code&gt; - shows all files and folders available, including the hidden ones including (.) current dir as well as (..) parent dir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls -lh&lt;/code&gt; - size of files are now more human readable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls -lS&lt;/code&gt; - lists files sorted by file size in descending order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls -ltr&lt;/code&gt; - lists files sorted by modification time (-r for reverse order).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls -m&lt;/code&gt; - delimits file list with &amp;lsquo;,&amp;rsquo; commas. (see &amp;ndash;FORMAT flag for more info)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls -R&lt;/code&gt; - Recursively lists files and folders. (you can pair -l with it too.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls *.mp3&lt;/code&gt; - filter out any file extension similarly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-A&lt;/code&gt; - lists all, excluding (.) current dir as well as (..) parent dir.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt; - lists directories and not their contents. eg: &lt;code&gt;ls -d */&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-r&lt;/code&gt; - for showing output in reverse order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-f&lt;/code&gt; - ls -a as unsorted and color mode disabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-i&lt;/code&gt; - print inode values (index numbers) of files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-g&lt;/code&gt; - omits owner column from listing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-i&lt;/code&gt; - print inode values (index numbers) of files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-n&lt;/code&gt; - user and group id&#39;s displayed as numeric values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-N&lt;/code&gt; - print file names without quotes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-X&lt;/code&gt; - sort listing by extension in ascending order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;color&lt;/code&gt; - add color to output. values = &amp;lsquo;auto&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;none&amp;rsquo; etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;file-type&lt;/code&gt; - same as &lt;code&gt;ls *.mp3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--full-time&lt;/code&gt; - shows time in full ISO formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--help&lt;/code&gt; - display this help and exit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--version&lt;/code&gt; - output version information and exit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; command &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;here.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or run &lt;code&gt;man ls&lt;/code&gt; on your terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-awesome-tools-to-consider&#34;&gt;Some awesome tools to consider:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lsd&lt;/strong&gt; - A color coded version of the ls command. Available as a snap package on the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;snapstore&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cheat&lt;/strong&gt; - lists usage for popular commands in *nix systems &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Github&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cheat ls
# Displays everything in the target directory
ls path/to/the/target/directory

# Displays everything including hidden files
ls -a

# Displays all files, along with the size (with unit suffixes) and timestamp
ls -lh

# Display files, sorted by size
ls -S

# Display directories only
ls -d */

# Display directories only, include hidden
ls -d .*/ */

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;manly&lt;/strong&gt; - great for understanding command options without having to open manpage &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; Github&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ manly ls -logX

ls - list directory contents
============================

      -g     like -l, but do not list owner

      -l     use a long listing format

      -o     like -l, but do not list group information

      -X     sort alphabetically by entry extension
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dgplug Homework</title>
      <link>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/dgplug-homework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 23:46:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://snbk97.github.io/posts/dgplug-homework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I joined dgplug foss summer training, few days back as I was quite fascinated with the concept of FOSS and Open Source in general. It is always my dream, to have my patch accepted in some FOSS project and watch it get used in daily life by others.
It has been an amazing experience overall. There is a lot to learn in this world. I believe I have started taking small steps towards learning new stuff in  this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, being in this training, there is a lot of material to read and comprehend. As the training progresses over IRC, it becomes cumbersome to keep tracks of the homework and links that we get to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here&#39;s a little bookmarklet I made to help to figure out the links and messages containing the word homework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag and place it on your bookmark bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open IRC chat logs and click the bookmarklet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your homework for the day, await at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;script type=&#34;application/javascript&#34; src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/snbk97/a2929ad03514e7955815b4c33a156e06.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
